Guide to the Bidwell Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Barnabas Bidwell (1763-1833), 1782-1868, 1926-1944; 1782-1833; Series I
  - Correspondence
    - Bidwell, Mary Gray (8), 1807 June-July (Box 1, Folder 13, Reel 1U)
    - Bidwell, Mary Gray (6), 1807 September-October (Box 1, Folder 14, Reel 1U)
    - Bidwell, Mary Gray (2), 1808 (Box 1, Folder 15, Reel 1U)
    - Bidwell, Sarah Gray (Sally) (7), 1806-1809 (Box 1, Folder 16, Reel 1U)
    - Binney, Horace (1), 1798 December 10 (Box 1, Folder 17, Reel 1U)
    - Davis, Daniel (1), 1809 July 18 (Box 1, Folder 18, Reel 1U)
    - Devotion, Ebenezer (1), 1805 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 19, Reel 1U)
    - Devotion, John (1), 1788 January 30 (Box 1, Folder 20, Reel 1U)
    - Incomplete letter from Mary Gray Bidwell to Sally Hunt, completed by Barnabas (1), 1808 January (Box 1, Folder 21, Reel 1U)
    - Huntington, Samuel (1), 1807 November 30 (Box 1, Folder 22, Reel 1U)
    - Kingston Presbyterian Church: letter of resignation from the Board of Trustees accompanied by an explanation re: county treasurer suit in Massachusetts (2), 1817 August 14 (Box 1, Folder 23, Reel 1U)
    - Larned, Colonel Simon (1), 1810 March 26 (Box 1, Folder 24, Reel 1U)
    - Partridge, Jemima (Bidwell) (1), 1788 February 1 (Box 1, Folder 25, Reel 1U)
    - Ridont, Sir Thomas, Surveyor General (1), 1828 May 9 (Box 1, Folder 26, Reel 1U)
    - Sewall, Henry D. (1), 1831 February 26 (Box 1, Folder 27, Reel 1U)
    - Smith, William (2), 1821 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 28, Reel 1U)
    - Spring, Marshall (2), 1806 June 23 (Box 1, Folder 29, Reel 1U)
    - Whitney, Mercy (Partridge), missionary in Hawaii (1), 1830 August 21 (Box 1, Folder 30, Reel 1U)
    - Whitaker, Thomas (1), Undated (Box 1, Folder 31, Reel 1U)
  - Correspondence Regarding Barnabas Bidwell
    - William P. Walker to Adonijah Bid-well re: Barnabas Bidwell's power of attorney for his brother (1), 1818 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 32, Reel 1U)
    - Adonijah S. Bidwell to Josiah Brewer re: B.B. and J. Wood-bridge [copy] (1), 1819 (Box 1, Folder 33, Reel 1U)
    - Ezekiel Bacon to M. S. Bidwell re: life of B. B. [empty], 1833 August 28 (Box 1, Folder 34, Reel 1U)
      General note
      See: box 3, folder 98
    - Adonijah Bidwell to M. S. Bidwell re: life of B. B. [empty], 1833 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 35, Reel 1U)
      See: box 3, folder 99
    - W. P. Walker to M. S. Bidwell re: life of B. B. [empty] (Box 1, Folder 36, Reel 1U)
      See: box 3, folder 129
    - Orlando Curtis Bidwell to Clara Bidwell Warren re: life of Barnabas Bidwell (1), 1926 (Box 1, Folder 37, Reel 1U)
    - Irving H. Gamwill, Clerk of the Courts, Berkshire County (Massachusetts), to Gertrude H. Bidwell re: case against Barnabas Bidwell [copy] (1), 1940 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 38, Reel 1U)
    - Edwin E. Horsey to Mrs. Charles A. Bidwell re: Barnabas Bidwell in Canada (3), 1942 January 19 (Box 1, Folder 39, Reel 1U)
    - Grace T. Hawksley, Clerk of the Courts, Northampton, Mass., to Mrs. C. A. Bidwell re: County of Berkshire vs. Barnabas Bidwell (1), 1942 May 8 (Box 1, Folder 40, Reel 1U)
    - Charles S. O'Connor to Mrs. Charles A. Bidwell re: Common-wealth of Massachusetts vs. Barnabas Bidwell (1), 1944 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 41, Reel 1U)
  - Writings By and About Barnabas Bidwell
    - "A Rainy Day," a poem by Barnabas Bidwell re: Mary, his deceased wife., Undated (Box 1, Folder 42, Reel 1U)
      General
      Mrs. Bidwell died in 1808; B. B. died in 1838.
    - "The Berkshire Looking Glass," a political satire by Ethan Stone, Circa 1864 (Box 1, Folder 43, Reel 1U)
    - "Nathan Jackson's Thanksgiving," mentioning Barnabas Bidwell, 1868 (Box 1, Folder 44, Reel 1U)
    - Clippings re: the case of Barnabas Bidwell, 1939-1956 (Box 1, Folder 45, Reel 1U)
    - Excerpt from History of the U. S. During the Administration of James Madison, by Henry Adams, Vol. 1, mentioning B. Bidwell, Undated (Box 1, Folder 46, Reel 1U)
  - Diplomas, Legal Documents and Financial Records
    - Yale diplomas of B. Bidwell, Master of Arts, Bachelor of Arts, 1785, 1788 (Box 2, Folder 47, Reel 1U)
    - Marriage paper of Barnabas Bidwell and Mary Gray, 1793 February 21 (Box 2, Folder 48, Reel 1U)
    - Deed to land in Union, N. Y., 1800 May 27 (Box 2, Folder 49, Reel 1U)
    - Brown University diploma of B. Bidwell, Doctor of Laws, 1805 (Box 2, Folder 50, Reel 1U)
    - Promissory note to B. Bidwell from E. Brown, E. Williams, and J. Hunt, for $1800, 1810 (Box 2, Folder 51, Reel 1U)
    - Power of attorney to Wm. P. Walker, 1810 August 8 (Box 2, Folder 52, Reel 1U)
    - Writ to attach the estate of B. Bidwell, 1810 October (Box 2, Folder 53, Reel 1U)
    - Account with Berkshire County, Massachusetts, 1810 December-1815 April (Box 2, Folder 54, Reel 1U)
    - Records of the Supreme Judicial Court (Suffolk), March term 1812 re: B. Bidwell, 1812-1812 (Box 2, Folder 55, Reel 1U)
    - Sheriff deed (1814); warranty deed (1816) re: real estate of B. Bidwell, 1814-1816 (Box 2, Folder 56, Reel 1U)
    - Power of attorney to Adonijah Bidwell, 1818 February 3 (Box 2, Folder 57, Reel 1U)
    - Canada
      - Abstract, lot 107, Kingston, 1800-1869 (Box 2, Folder 58, Reel 1U)
      - Papers relating to the Bidwell house at Bath, formerly owned by Solomon Johns, 1807-1830 (Box 2, Folder 59, Reel 1U)
      - Mortgage, leases, and deed of John Switzer, 1812-1828 (Box 2, Folder 60, Reel 1U)
      - Deeds: P. Davy to B. Bidwell and A. Perkins; A. Perkins to B. Bidwell (Ernest-town); bond for a deed, B. Bidwell to A. Perkins, 1813, 1815 (Box 2, Folder 61, Reel 1U)
      - Title to McDonnell lot in Kingston, 1816 May 28 (Box 2, Folder 62, Reel 1U)
      - Title to McLaughlin lot in Kingston, 1816 February 19 (Box 2, Folder 63, Reel 1U)
      - Papers relating to lot 98, Kingston, Francis Roucheleau to B. Bidwell, 1818-1825 (Box 2, Folder 64, Reel 1U)
        - Oversize material, 1818-1825 (Box 18)
      - Deeds to Cobourg property: David Washburn to B. Bidwell, Timothy Kittridge to David Washburn and Charles Short, 1820 January 4 (Box 2, Folder 65, Reel 1U)
      - Records of lot 98, city of Kingston, 1818-1839 (Box 2, Folder 66, Reel 1U)
      - Simeon Morrill Papers re: lot 19, Kingston (Box 2, Folder 67, Reel 1U)
      - Deeds and papers relating to Cobourg, received from D. Washburn, 1819, 1820, 1826 (Box 2, Folder 68, Reel 1U)
      - Unsigned copy of a covenant of indemnification given by B. Bidwell to Edward Henderson re: Cobourg property, 1820 January (Box 2, Folder 69, Reel 1U)
      - Deed to Kingston lot 398, Solomon Johns to B. Bidwell, 1820 August 15 (Box 2, Folder 70, Reel 1U)
      - Agreements and leases, Kingston, 1820-1822 (Box 2, Folder 71, Reel 1U)
      - Patrick Smyth estate papers, 1820-1829 (Box 2, Folder 72, Reel 1U)
      - Deed: Susanah Bean to B. Bidwell, 1821 March 9 (Box 2, Folder 73, Reel 1U)
      - Receipts for deeds, 1821, 1824 (Box 2, Folder 74, Reel 1U)
      - Deed of bargain and sale (Cobourg property) and release of dower, Robert and Margaret Richardson to B. Bidwell, 1825 May 5 (Box 2, Folder 75, Reel 1U)
      - Record of two deeds and a will registered, 1821, 1822, 1830 (Box 2, Folder 76, Reel 1U)
      - Leases of Cobourg property, 1821, 1828-1833 (Box 2, Folder 77, Reel 1U)
      - Release of dower (Cobourg property), Lurana Kittridge to B. Bidwell, 1822 January 10 (Box 2, Folder 78, Reel 1U)
      - Deed of release; grant and confirmation, Penuel G. Tilden to B. Bidwell, 1822 March 30 (Box 2, Folder 79, Reel 1U)
      - Deed of bargain and sale, Thomas Paxton to B. Bidwell, 1822 August 17 (Box 2, Folder 80, Reel 1U)
      - Accounts and memos re: Canadian Business matters, 1822-1836, undated (Box 2, Folder 81, Reel 1U)
      - Assignment of a lease, Simeon Morrill to B. Bidwell, 1824 April 21 (Box 2, Folder 82, Reel 1U)
      - Deed of bargain and sale, Barnabas Bidwell to Wm. Smith [empty], 1834 August 2 (Box 2, Folder 83, Reel 1U)
        See: box 4, folder 172
      - D. Dunham's deed to E. Bachus, witnessed by B. Bidwell [empty] (Box 2, Folder 84, Reel 1U)
        - Oversize, 1824 September 8 (Box 18, Reel 1U)
      - Deed of bargain and sale, Jeremiah Lapp to B. Bidwell (Cobourg property), 1825 May 14 (Box 2, Folder 85, Reel 1U)
      - Deed of bargain and sale, Simeon Morrill to B. Bidwell, 1825 July 14 (Box 2, Folder 86, Reel 1U)
      - Joseph Caverly's will, witnessed by B. Bidwell, 1829 March 3 (Box 2, Folder 87, Reel 1U)
      - Land leased by B. Bidwell, 1829, 1830 (Box 2, Folder 88, Reel 1U)
      - Deed of bargain and sale, John Stuart Smyth to Barnabas Bidwell, 1830 April 13 (Box 2, Folder 89, Reel 1U)
      - Sheriff's certifications of land purchases made by B. Bidwell in Kingston, 1830 (Box 2, Folder 90, Reel 1U)
      - Deeds of bargain and sale, Kingston land at public auction, 1831 (Box 2, Folder 91, Reel 1U)
      - Probate of the last will and testament of Barnabas Bidwell, 1834 January 28 (Box 2, Folder 92, Reel 1U)
      - Plan of property at Cobourg, Undated (Box 2, Folder 93, Reel 1U)
      - Survey of property at Cobourg, Undated (Box 2, Folder 94, Reel 1U)
      - Inventory of the estate of B. Bidwell, Undated (Box 2, Folder 95, Reel 1U)
      - Legal documents of others pertaining to Bidwell land purchases [empty] (Box 2, Folder 96, Reel 1U)
        See: box 4, folder 193-210
- Marshall Spring Bidwell (1799-1872), 1790-1890; 1807-1872; Series II
  This series contains all material in the collection written by or about Marshall Spring Bidwell.
  The series is divided into six sub-sections:
  Correspondence of M. S. Bidwell
  Correspondence Regarding M. S. Bidwell and His Finances
  Writings of M. S. Bidwell Writings Regarding M. S. Bidwell
  Certificates, Legal Documents and Finances
  Legal Papers of Others
  "Correspondence of M. S. Bidwell" includes letters to and from Marshall Spring Bidwell, grouped together and arranged alphabetically by the correspondent's last name. All other subsections are arranged chronologically.
  "Legal Papers of Others" consists primarily of original grants of land and previous deeds to property subsequently owned by the Bidwells. As stated above, they are arranged chronologically.
  - Correspondence of Marshall S. Bidwell
    - Armstrong, Dr. E. W. with copy of last will and testament of William Willcox, father of Mrs. Clara W. Bidwell (1), 1844 August 22 (Box 3, Folder 97, Reel 2U)
    - Bacon, Ezekiel re: Barnabas Bidwell (1), 1833 August 28 (Box 3, Folder 98, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Adonijah (1761-1837) re: Barnabas Bidwell (1), 1833 September 16 (Box 3, Folder 99, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Barnabas (6), 1806-1830 (Box 3, Folder 100, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Clara W. (2), 1822, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 101, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Clara W. (6), 1834 (Box 3, Folder 102, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Clara W. (18), 1835 (Box 3, Folder 103, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Clara W. (15), 1836 (Box 3, Folder 104, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Clara W. (14), 1839, 1842, 1848 (Box 3, Folder 105, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Clara W. (16), 1849, 1851 (Box 3, Folder 105a, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Lawson Dench (2), 1831, 1840 (Box 3, Folder 106, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Marshall Spring, Jr. (Circa15), 1865-1868, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 107, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Mary Gray [includes a letter to her mother, Sarah Gray] (1), 1807 June 7 (Box 3, Folder 108, Reel 2U)
    - Bidwell, Orlando B., including quit-claim deed of J. C. Easton and wife (2), 1870 March 19 (Box 3, Folder 109, Reel 2U)
    - Brewer, Edwin (1), 1811 April 6 (Box 3, Folder 110, Reel 2U)
    - Brewer, Josiah [empty], 1868 (Box 3, Folder 111, Reel 2U)
      See: box 5, folder 219
    - Butler, Orange re: Canadian rebellion (1), 1837 (Box 3, Folder 112, Reel 2U)
    - Conger, Wilson S. re: Cobourg property (3), 1833, 1834 (Box 3, Folder 113, Reel 2U)
    - Dickinson, James T. re: Taylor genealogy [empty] (Box 3, Folder 114, Reel 2U)
      See: box 6, folder 245
    - Handy, Henry S. re: Canadian Rebellion (1), 1837 December 13 (Box 3, Folder 115, Reel 2U)
    - Head, Sir Francis Bond, Lieutenant, Governor of Upper Canada (1), 1838 March 23 (Box 3, Folder 116, Reel 2U)
    - Knox, Alice W. re: Knox-Jenks family record [empty], 1867 (Box 3, Folder 117, Reel 2U)
      See: box 5, folder 237
    - Machan, John (1), Undated (Box 3, Folder 118, Reel 2U)
    - Murdock, Thomas, Chief Secretary to the Governor General of Upper Canada re: conditions for M. S. B.'s return (1), 1840 April 21 (Box 3, Folder 119, Reel 2U)
    - Partridge, (Jemima?) re: genealogy (1), 1838 March 10 (Box 3, Folder 120, Reel 2U)
    - Prentiss, Douglass re: Canadian property (1), 1860 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 121, Reel 2U)
    - Prentiss, G. R. re: Canadian property (1), 1864 June 22 (Box 3, Folder 122, Reel 2U)
    - Robb, John re: Kingston property (1), 1870 March 26 (Box 3, Folder 123, Reel 2U)
    - Sewall, Henry D. re: Canadian property (2), 1864 June 22 (Box 3, Folder 124, Reel 2U)
    - Smith, John J. re: M. S. B.'s return to Canada (1), 1840 February 11 (Box 3, Folder 125, Reel 2U)
    - Taylor, Henry W. re: Taylor genealogy [empty], 1868 (Box 3, Folder 126, Reel 2U)
      See: box 6, folder 244
    - Thompson, Charles Towlett, Governor General of Upper Canada (copy of M. S. B.'s appeal for redress) (1), 1840 March 17 (Box 3, Folder 127, Reel 2U)
    - Turney, P. M. re: mortgages (2), 1850 January (Box 3, Folder 128, Reel 2U)
    - Walker, (Judge) W. P. re: Barnabas Bidwell (1), 1833 September 26 (Box 3, Folder 129, Reel 2U)
    - Whitaker, Thomas (1), 1824 February 17 (Box 3, Folder 130, Reel 2U)
    - Williams, S. Wells re: life in China, visits to Japan with Perry's expedition (4) (Box 3, Folder 131, Reel 2U)
    - M. S. B. to unidentified (1), 1816 April 24 (Box 3, Folder 132, Reel 2U)
  - Correspondence Regarding Marshall S. Bidwell and His Finances
    - Correspondence of Henry D. Sewall and Henry Cassidy re: Bidwell's Canadian property (4), 1835, 1837 (Box 3, Folder 133, Reel 2U)
    - Letter from Simon MacKenzie to E. Murney re: Canadian property (1), 1836 February (Box 3, Folder 134, Reel 2U)
    - Hensey, Charles to Prentiss, Douglass re: Bidwell's Canadian property (1), 1836 November (Box 3, Folder 135, Reel 2U)
    - Letter from John Prince to (?) Woodruff re: M. S. B.'s return to Canada (1), 1840 (Box 3, Folder 136, Reel 2U)
    - Correspondence re: Bidwell land in Hawkesbury (5), 1854-1856 (Box 3, Folder 137, Reel 2U)
    - Correspondence of D. Prentiss and E. Murney re: M. S. B.'s Canadian property (3), 1855 (Box 3, Folder 138, Reel 2U)
    - Letter of William Angelin to D. Prentiss re: unpaid taxes on Bidwell's Kingston property (1), 1856 December 18 (Box 3, Folder 139, Reel 2U)
    - Correspondence between Douglass Prentiss and Andrew Russell, Asst. Commissioner of Crown Lands, re: Bidwell Canadian property (3), 1856, 1858 (Box 3, Folder 140, Reel 2U)
    - Letter to Yale College submitting Marshall S. Bidwell as candidate for Doctor of Laws (1), 1858 (Box 3, Folder 141, Reel 2U)
    - Correspondence re: Kingston lot 98 (copy) (1), 1867 June 20 (Box 3, Folder 142, Reel 2U)
    - E. Ryerson to Judge Neilson re: life of Marshall S. Bidwell (1), 1872 December (Box 3, Folder 143, Reel 2U)
    - Fragment of a letter to Governor General Charles Towlett Thompson on behalf of M. S. B. urging that he be appointed to the Bench of Judges (1), Undated (Box 3, Folder 144, Reel 2U)
  - Writings of Marshall S. Bidwell
    - "Speech on the Intestate Estate Bill in the Provincial Assembly of Upper Canada", 1831 January 24 (Box 3, Folder 145, Reel 2U)
    - "Explanation to Friends" re: circumstances of his departure from Upper Canada, 1838 January 17 (Box 3, Folder 146, Reel 2U)
    - Verses written to Marshall S. Bidwell, Jr. on the death of an infant son, [1872 Sep] (Box 3, Folder 147, Reel 2U)
  - Writings Regarding Marshall S. Bidwell
    - Clippings: Marshall S. Bidwell and rebellion in Upper Canada, 1837, 1862, undated (Box 3, Folder 148, Reel 2U)
    - "The Cause and Circumstances of Mr. Bidwell's Banishment by Sir F. B. Head, correctly stated and proved by a United Empire Loyalist", 1838 (Box 3, Folder 149, Reel 2U)
    - Clippings: obituaries, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 150, Reel 2U)
    - Sermon preached at the funeral services of Marshall S. Bidwell, by the Rev. Robert Russell Booth, D.D., 1872 (Box 3, Folder 151, Reel 2U)
    - In Memoriam: Marshall S. Bidwell, N.Y. Bar and Court of Appeals, 1872 November 2 (Box 3, Folder 152, Reel 2U)
    - In Memoriam, issued by the session of the First Presbyterian Church, Freeport, Illinois, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 153, Reel 2U)
    - Memorial tributes to Marshall S. Bidwell, 1872 (Box 3, Folder 154, Reel 2U)
    - "Marshall S. Bidwell, A Memoir," by Edward F. de Lancey, New York Genealogical and Biographical Record, 1890 January (Box 3, Folder 155, Reel 2U)
    - Clippings: "Portraits of the Bar," a description of M. S. Bidwell. [empty] (Box 3, Folder 156, Reel 2U)
      See: box 13, folder 464
    - Unidentified quotation re: M. S. Bidwell in Canada, Undated (Box 3, Folder 157, Reel 2U)
    - "The Maternal Ancestors of Marshall Spring Bidwell" [empty], Undated (Box 3, Folder 158, Reel 2U)
      See: box 6, folder 242
  - Certificates, Legal Documents and Finances of Marshall Spring Bidwell
    - Certificate of M. S. Bidwell's birth, attested to by the town clerk, Luther Plumb, 1815 (Box 4, Folder 159, Reel 2U)
    - Certificate of marriage between Marshall S. Bidwell and Clara Willcox, 1818 September 1 (Box 4, Folder 160, Reel 2U)
    - Clerkship of M. S. Bidwell, 1820, 1821 (Box 4, Folder 161, Reel 2U)
    - Certificate of the Law Society of Upper Canada, 1821 (Box 4, Folder 162, Reel 2U)
    - Certification as an attorney, 1821-1834 (Box 4, Folder 163, Reel 2U)
    - Deed of assignment in trust, Thomas S. Whitaker to M. S. Bidwell, 1824 (Box 4, Folder 164, Reel 2U)
    - Deed and mortgages, Wilson S. Conger and Thomas Scott--Sarah Gray and Marshall Spring Bidwell re: Cobourg property, 1830 (Box 4, Folder 165, Reel 2U)
    - Unsigned release, M. S. Bidwell, S. G. Bidwell--Samuel McCrae, Anthony McGuin, 1830 (Box 4, Folder 166, Reel 2U)
    - Last will and testament of H. Yeoman, M. S. Bidwell, executor, 1832 May 20 (Box 4, Folder 167, Reel 2U)
    - Conner vs. Burley, M. S. Bidwell, attorney for the plaintiff, 1832 (Box 4, Folder 168, Reel 2U)
    - Deed, Franklin Jackes to M. S. Bidwell, 1833 March 5 (Box 4, Folder 169, Reel 2U)
    - Deed of release and related papers, James Radcliffe to Sarah Gray and Marshall Spring Bidwell re: Cobourg property, 1833 November 25 (Box 4, Folder 170, Reel 2U)
    - Bond of Wilson S. Conger and Thomas Scott of Cobourg to Marshall S. Bidwell and Sarah Gray Bidwell (copy), 1834 April 25 (Box 4, Folder 171, Reel 2U)
    - Deed William Smith to M. S. and Sarah Gray Bidwell. Also includes deed from B. Bidwell to William Smith, 1834 August 2, 1824 June 17 (Box 4, Folder 172, Reel 2U)
    - Deed of bargain and sale, G. Crookshank and J. B. Macaulay to M. S. Bidwell, 1837 August 7 (Box 4, Folder 173, Reel 2U)
    - Licenses to practice law in N. Y. State, 1838 January (Box 4, Folder 174, Reel 2U)
    - Leases to Bidwell property in Kingston, 1839, 1855 (Box 4, Folder 175, Reel 2U)
    - Mortgage and bond, John Roaf to M. S. Bidwell, 1840 (Box 4, Folder 176, Reel 2U)
    - Deeds and releases M. S. and Sarah Gray Bidwell--Mary Eliza Cassady and others, 1840, 1857 (Box 4, Folder 177, Reel 2U)
    - Records of Bidwell Canadian property, Circa 1840-1863 (Box 4, Folder 178, Reel 2U)
    - Doctor of Laws, Union College [empty] (Box 4, Folder 179, Reel 3U)
      - Oversize, 1843 (Box 19, Reel 3U)
    - Mortgage, John Rolph and wife to M. S. Bidwell, 1844 August 1 (Box 4, Folder 180, Reel 3U)
    - Kingston stock records, 1844-1849 (Box 4, Folder 181, Reel 3U)
    - Deed, M. S. and Clara Bidwell to Andrew Clancy, 1845 (Box 4, Folder 182, Reel 3U)
    - Certificate of honorary membership to the American Board of Commissioners for Foreign Missions, 1848 February 4 (Box 4, Folder 183, Reel 3U)
    - Murray mortgage, release, 1850 February (Box 4, Folder 184, Reel 3U)
    - Release, M. S. Bidwell to Thomas Cummings and James Pollock, 1850 March 1 (Box 4, Folder 185, Reel 3U)
    - Taxes paid in Kingston by M. S. Bidwell, 1850-1854 (Box 4, Folder 186, Reel 3U)
    - Memos re: land in Hawkesbury, 1855, undated (Box 4, Folder 187, Reel 3U)
    - Yale Doctor of Laws degree [empty] (Box 4, Folder 188, Reel 3U)
      - Oversize, 1858 (Box 19, Reel 3U)
    - Notes of W. R. Wells to M. S Bidwell ($700.00), 1859 July 1 (Box 4, Folder 189, Reel 3U)
    - Mortgage and deed, Anthony Dennis--M. S. and Sara Gray Bidwell, 1859 (Box 4, Folder 190, Reel 3U)
    - Bidwell Minnesota land, 1859-1873 (Box 4, Folder 191, Reel 3U)
    - Authorization to Guy R. Prentiss, 1863 (Box 4, Folder 192, Reel 3U)
    - Attorney and counsellor of the Supreme Court [empty] (Box 4, Folder 193, Reel 3U)
      - Oversize, 1864 (Box 19, Reel 3U)
    - Last will and testament of M. S. Bidwell (copy), 1871 August 16 (Box 4, Folder 194, Reel 3U)
    - Probate of the last will and testament of M. S. Bidwell, 1872 (Box 4, Folder 195, Reel 3U)
  - Legal Papers of Others
    - Grant of land to David Day [empty] (Box 4, Folder 196, Reel 3U)
      - Oversize, 1798 April 19 (Box 18, Reel 3U)
    - Deed (Union, N. Y. land) Edward and John Paterson to Uriah Simons, 1796 January 25 (Box 4, Folder 197, Reel 3U)
    - Grant of land to James Rainey [empty] (Box 4, Folder 198, Reel 3U)
      - Oversize, 1803 February (Box 18, Reel 3U)
    - Grant of land to David Barry [empty] (Box 4, Folder 199, Reel 3U)
      - Oversize, 1804 January (Box 18, Reel 3U)
    - Grant of land to Richard Cartwright (copy), 1805 September 4 (Box 4, Folder 200, Reel 3U)
    - Grant of land to Elizabeth Buis [empty] (Box 4, Folder 201, Reel 3U)
      - Oversize, 1805 October 7 (Box 18, Reel 3U)
    - Last will and testament of Mary Lines, sister of William McLaughlin, 1813 (Box 4, Folder 202, Reel 3U)
    - Last will and testament of William Fairfield, probate of the will, 1816 (Box 4, Folder 203, Reel 3U)
    - Algie and Drennan vs. William McLaughlin, 1817 (Box 4, Folder 204, Reel 3U)
    - Exemplification of a patent to Francis Z. Rochleau for a town lot in Kingston [empty] (Box 4, Folder 205, Reel 3U)
      - Oversize, 1819 March 3 (Box 18, Reel 3U)
    - Bond, Dan Peter and John Switzer to Thomas Whitaker and John Brown, 1821 August 21 (Box 4, Folder 206, Reel 3U)
    - Promissory note, Norwell Comstock and Pamela Mench to Samuel Weethon, 1821 (Box 4, Folder 207, Reel 3U)
    - Grant of land to Stephen Miles [empty] (Box 4, Folder 208, Reel 3U)
      - Oversize, 1825 July (Box 18, Reel 3U)
    - Deed James and Marey Crowther to Charles Thompson, 1826 (Box 4, Folder 209, Reel 3U)
    - Deed Solomon Walker to Herman Fairfield, 1834 July 19 (Box 4, Folder 210, Reel 3U)
- Correspondence and Personal Papers of Other Bidwell and Related Families, 1750-1952; 1850-1915; Series III
  This series contains the correspondence, writings, notebooks, diaries, legal papers, clippings and photographs of Bidwell family members spanning six generations. The series is divided into three subsections: "Bidwell Family, General," "Bidwell Family, Individual Members," "Correspondence, Writings, and Photographs of Others."
  "Bidwell Family, General" contains genealogical and historical materials on the Bidwells and related families, which is arranged alphabetically by the family's last name. There is also material on (Tyringham) Monterey, Massachusetts, the Bidwell ancestral home, which is arranged chronologically. In addition, there are family materials which cannot be ascribed to one particular individual, including writings and memorabilia, which is arranged alphabetically by family name; and photos, also arranged alphabetically by family name.